COLIN GROARK

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with experience untangling problems and developing efficient systems and tools for programs and teams in the private and non-profit sectors. I want to collaborate with a driven team to craft innovative tools that offer a host of solutions to the complexities of everyday life.

CONTACT

∠ colingroark@gmail.com

colingroark.com

♀ Seattle, Washington

in colin-groark/

? cgroark

EDUCATION

General Assembly Web Development Immersive Training 2018

University of Washington, Evans School of Public Policy and Governance MPA Environmental Policy and Natural Resource Management Certificate Environmental Management

Trinity College BA International Studies, Hispanic Studies

EMPLOYMENT

General Assembly

Full-Stack Web Develope

Seattle, Washington Nov 2017 to Current

12-week immersive full-stack web development training with 480 hours of instruction Completed four projects drawing on RESTful APIs and technologies that include React, MongoDB, PostreSQL, Node.js, JQuery, Python, JavaScript, HTML and CSS Worked with cross-functional teams of developers and designers to bring week-long and quick turnaround projects to fruition

Tilth Alliance (Seattle Tilth)

Seattle, Washington Aug 2015 to Nov 2017

Director, Community Education and Environmental Programs Aug 2015 to Not Oversaw Tilth Alliance outreach and education programs on resource conservation, urban gardening and restoration

Managed 11 person team and \$890K grant and contract portfolio that funded seven core programs

Developed processes to track program deliverables, grant applications and reporting Built budget tracking systems in Excel to monitor program expenditures; and SharePoint metrics tracker to monitor program impact

Led proposal strategy and client interview to secure 5-year \$2.2 million resource conservation contract with Seattle Public Utilities

Member of leadership team focused on strategy, financial health and program direction

EnviroIssues

Seattle, Washingotn Apr 2013 to Aug 2015

Business Development Associate

Managed business development and marketing team for community outreach consulting firm Led proposal teams and supported strategy and content to compete for public projects throughout the Pacific Northwest

Created metrics dashboard and data analysis tools to better assess proposal trends and outcomes

Basel Action Network

Research Intern

Seattle, Washington Apr 2010 to Mar 2011

Conducted research and drafted reports on the illegal trafficking of electronic waste Developed data calculator for app to measure environmental benefits of recycling electronics

Management Systems International

Business Development Associate and Consultant

Washington, DC Sep 2009 to Jul 2012, Aug 2007 to Aug 2009

Coordinated proposal teams to compete for foreign aid projects up to \$21 million across seven sectors

Managed teams of mid and senior staff to capture technical proposal components within strict deadlines

Provided budgetary, recruitment and report-writing support for complex international aid contracts

The Umoja Centre

Strategy Design and Fundraising Officer

Arusha, Tanzania Jan 2011 to Mar 2011

Assisted in the research and writing of grant proposals for education and solar power programs Co-led design and implementation of a 30-day fundraising plan that raised nearly \$20,000

ECC Foreign Language Institute

Tokyo, Japan Aug 2009 to Aug 2010

Taught conversational English for classes of up to 10 adults and 30 children

SKILLS

English Teache

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPMENT: React, JavaScript, JQuery, ES6, CSS, HTML BACK-END WEB DEVELOPMENT: PostgreSQL, Node.js, Python, Django, MongoDB